<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aayush Gupta</title>
    <link>https://aayushgupta.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aayush Gupta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 [Aayush Gupta](https://aayushgupta.dev)</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://aayushgupta.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aayushgupta.dev/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aayushgupta.dev/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://aayushgupta.dev/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aayushgupta.dev/work/</guid>
      <description>Work Software Engineer 2 Flipkart Internet Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru India October 2022 - Present
Monetization: Supported enhancements to the Rewards and Gamification systems for improved monetization potential.
Undertook initiatives to improve the Resiliency and Fault Tolerance of the systems though signalling and auto-recovery mechanisms.
Wrote detailed SOPs and RunBooks for handling database and application maintenance activities. Automated most of these workflows which reduced the frquency of downtimes due to human error and faster Mean-Time-To-Recovery (MTTR) from production incidents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Contributions</title>
      <link>https://aayushgupta.dev/oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aayushgupta.dev/oss/</guid>
      <description>Varadhi - A message bus implementation with a REST Interface Involved in the effort to open-source our in-house Kafka-based REST-Bus platform. Rebuilding from scratch as a cloud-native offering supporting multiple message bus implementations like Kakfa, Pulsar, and Google Cloud Pub-Sub.
Contributions
Evaluated Zookeeper as a metadata storage by benchmarking the performance of creation and access of large number of znodes.
Published the evaluation report and recommended hardware specifications for utilizing Zookeeper as a metadata store for Varadhi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://aayushgupta.dev/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aayushgupta.dev/projects/</guid>
      <description>wcgo - A GNU wc clone in Go wcgo is a Go implementation of the classic wc (word count) command-line tool, providing a fast and efficient way to count words, lines, and characters in text files. The aim is to offer functionality similar to wc while utilizing Go&amp;rsquo;s language features and concurrency model to get some extra performance.
kix - Dynamic, Interpreted language in Kotlin Following the Crafting Interpreters book, I created my own programming language implemented in Kotlin.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
